## Yuliia Dovbak Graduate Software Engineer

Athlone, Co. Westmeath

**Portfolio** 

LinkedIn

2002 - 2013

**Email** 

Tel

**Software Engineering Course** 

**Secondary School (Ukraine)** 

0858254699	yulia.dovbak@gmail.com	https://dovbak.com/	https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuliia- dovbak-7468631ba/
Personal summary Enthusiastic graduate software engineer with strong software engineering foundation. Have gained professional experience while working in Ericsson on summer internship and on 9-month placement. Worked in an agile environment on a highly technical project CBRS. During placement I improved my knowledge on cloud technologies and linux.			Areas of Expertise OOP
			nent. Java (3yrs)
			٠ , , ,
			HTML/CSS (1yrs)
<ul> <li>Awarded:</li> <li>Student of the Year 2021 in Technological University of the Shannon: Midlands Midwest</li> </ul>			Bootstrap (1 yr) e SQL (2yr) REST
<ul> <li>Student of the Year 2021 in the Faculty of Engineering and Informatics.</li> </ul>			
<ul> <li>Student of the Year 2022 in the Faculty of Engineering and Informatics.</li> </ul>			
Working as a TUS Student Ambassador, engaging with potential students on Open Days, trying to bring more females into the STEM courses and industries.			VS Code Android Studio vim (1 year)
Looking for a graduate software developer position in the field of Cloud.			
Education			
Technological University of Shannon: Midlands Midwest (former Athlone Institute of Technology)  BSc (Hons) in Software Design with Cloud Computing			Expected grad: May 2023 Stage GPA 2022: 96.33
Relevant Courses: Software Development (OOP), Agile Methodologies, Web Development, Databases, Maths, Android Mobile App Development, Design Patterns			
National Aviation University (Kyiv, Ukraine)			2013 - 2015

#### Languages:

English: fluentUkrainian: native

#### **Work Experience**

Ericsson Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

Co-op

Worked on CBRS technology.

Participated in adding support for TLS.

• Finished a course on Kubernetes Administration and was troubleshooting the k8s cluster.

Learned basic Linux, Vim, Docker commands.

# Technological University of Shannon: Midlands Midwest (former Athlone Institute of Technology)

Aug 2020 - Present

Student Ambassador

- Contributed to AIT CAO hub by writing blog posts and filming videos about my experience in college.
- Represented my course on Open Days.
- Held Campus Tours for students.

Ericsson Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Co-op

#### **Projects**

#### [Java] Newsagent Delivery System

https://github.com/Rayfitzpat/NewspaperDelivery

- Employed an **agile** process in a group of 5 people, used TDD, wrote **user stories**, **Junit** tests.
- During 3 sprints the team fulfilled most of the requirements and developed **SQL DB**, used **JDBC** to work with database data in java, implemented CLI and GUI interfaces (**Swing**).
- Had an experience to implement the role of **scrum master** in one sprint.

### [Web Development] Weather Website

dovbak.com/weather/

- Used **OpenWeather API** to get the weather forecast for today and next 7 days.
- Used **Leaflet** Javascript library to display the city searched by the user on the map component.
- Used **Charts.js** for visual representation of changes in temperature, humidity and cloudiness in the next 7 days.
- Used **Bootstrap** for styling of the website.

#### [Java] Connect 4

https://github.com/ydovbak/ConnectFour

- Connect Four developed in Java
- Used Swing for GUI (Graphics 2D)
- Employed recursive methods for identifying winning conditions